两年之后  突然有人敲门了
So two years later, there's a knock on the door.
那人打开门  看见门口立着只蜗牛
Guy opens it, and there on his porch is the snail,
蜗牛说  "这TM是怎么回事?"
who says, "What the heck was all that about?"
我不知道笑点在哪儿
I don't really get it.
你看  蜗牛花了两年的时间才...
Well, see, it took two years for the snail to...
那不重要
Not important.
-我能问你个问题吗  -当然
- Can I ask you a question?  - Sure.
你认为我们会发展到什么程度
Where do you think this is going?
老实说  我本来希望至少上个二垒
To be honest, I was hoping at least second base.
你真风趣
You're so funny.
你就像是个单口相声演员
You're like a stand-up comedian.
一个犹太单口相声演员  这很新鲜
A Jewish stand-up comedian, that'd be new.
事实上  我觉得他们当中很多都是犹太人
Actually, I think a lot of them are Jewish.
不  我只是  算了
No, I was just... Never mind.
霍华德  这是我们的第三次约会
Look, Howard, this is our third date
我们都知道这意味着什么
and we both know what that means.
-都知道吗  -性
- We do?  - Sex.
你开玩笑的吧
You're kidding.
但我需要知道你是要谈
But I need to know whether you're looking
一场恋爱还是要一夜情
for a relationship or a one-night stand.
好的  只是搞清楚点
Okay, just to be clear:
这个问题只有一个正确答案吗
there's only one correct answer, right?
而不是飞机选餐里的要"鸡肉还是鱼肉"
It's not like "chicken or fish" on an airplane?
也许你需要认真思考一下这个问题了
Maybe you need to think about it a little.
也不是没有过
You know, it's not unheard of
从一夜情发展为恋爱关系的事
for a one-night stand to turn into a relationship.
等你想明白了再给我打电话
Call me when you figure it out.
三次约会意味着性
Three dates means sex?
谁知道啊
Who knew?
向你致敬  宅男
Greetings, homies.
宅女
Homette.
为什么这么早就结束约会回来了
Why are you back from your date so early?
谈恋爱  就要跟在娱乐业一样
In romance, as in show business,
总是要让观众欲求不满
always leave them wanting more.
这到底是什么意思
What exactly does that mean?
他被三振出局了
He struck out.
生活大爆炸
第三季第九集
你们两个知道
Hey, did either of you guys know
与同一个女人约会三次
that three dates with the same woman
就可以上床的临界点?
is the threshold for sex?
事实上  我从未与同一女人约会三次
Actually, I've never had three dates with the same woman.
而我和佩妮花了两年
With Penny and me, it took two years.
现在认真回想一下  的确是三次约会
Now that I think about it, that was three dates.
好吧  那在你和佩妮搞上之前
Okay, well, before you and Penny hooked up,
她有没有要求什么承诺
Did she ask for any kind of commitment?
没  她倒是非常清楚地表示
No, she was pretty clear about
要有保持随时换人的权力
wanting to keep her options open.
我有东西要宣布一下
I have something to announce,
但是出于惯例  我会等你们
but out of respect for convention, I will wait for you
说完现在的话题
to finish your current conversation.
你们在聊什么呢
What are you talking about?
一种文化模式
The cultural paradigm in which people have sex
就是人们会在三次约会后做爱
after three dates.
原来如此
I see.
现在我们是说的"date"是指社交活动
Now, are we talking "date," the social interaction,
还是指干枣
or "date," the dried fruit?
算了  你要宣布什么
Never mind, what's your announcement?
很好  轮到我了  这令人非常兴奋
Oh, good, my turn. Well, this is very exciting
并且我想让你们最先知道
and I wanted you to be among the first to know...
嗨  库珀
Hey, Cooper.
我听说你下周要和《科学星期五》的
I hear you're going to be on the radio
艾拉·弗雷托上广播节目
with Ira Flatow from Science Friday next week.
谢谢  克瑞普克  剥夺了我跟我的朋友
Thank you, Kripke, for depriving me of the opportunity
分享这则新闻的机会
to share my news with my friends.
很荣幸
My pleasure.
我的"谢谢"可不是诚恳的
My "thank you" was not sincere.
但我的"很荣幸"是的
But "my pleasure" is.
让我问你个问题
Let me ask you a question:
什么时候国家公共广播
At what point did National Public Radio
不得不邀请一些废材
have to start scraping the bottom of the barrel
作为嘉宾呢
for its guests?
别回答  这是个比喻
Don't answer. It's rhetorical.
为什么你是个笨蛋
Why are you such a stupid head?
这也是个比喻
That is also rhetorical.
真抱歉你们不得不听到这些
I'm sorry you had to hear that.
你真的要上国家公共广播吗
Are you really going to be on NPR?
没错  他们通过我办公室的电话采访我
Yes, they're interviewing me by phone from my office,
问一些最近所谓的"发现"
regarding the recent so-called "discovery"
关于自旋冰中的磁单极子
of magnetic monopoles in spin-ices.
因为是誓言周  他们想通过一些辩论
It's pledge week and they're trying to goose the ratings
来提高收听率
with a little controversy.
真酷  恭喜你
Very cool, congratulations.
谢谢  我妈妈也非常兴奋
Thank you. My mother is very excited.
她召集了她的圣经学习小组来收听
She's convening her Bible study group to listen in,
然后为我的灵魂祈祷
and then pray for my soul.
我曾经上过一次电台
I was on the radio once.
我打进了新德里的狂热FM104的热线
I called in to Fever 104 FM New Delhi
成为了第四个说一句话就能拿钱的人
and was the fourth person to say the phrase that pays:
"狂热104   aajke naye  acchha sangeetka ghar."
"Fever 104, aajke naye  acchha sangeetka ghar."
意思是  "狂热104
That means: "Fever 104,
超棒流行音乐之家
home of the really good current music."
还是在印度语里说更拉风
It's much catchier in Hindi.
好的  这些是明天上国家公共广播
All right. These are the talking points
访谈的讲点
for my NPR interview tomorrow.
我必须确定它们对于那些
I need to make sure that they're simple enough
教育程度较低的听众来说也足够简单易懂
for the less educated in the audience to understand.
霍华德  看一遍然后告诉我你哪里不懂
Howard, look this over and tell me what's unclear to you.
劳驾  我有麻省理工大学的
Excuse me, I have a master's degree in engineering
工程硕士学位证书
from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology.
要求修完144个学分
It required the completion of 144 units of grad work
和一篇原创论文
and an original thesis.
没错
Yes.
看完告诉我有哪些不清楚的
Look this over and tell me what's unclear to you.
谢尔顿让你做事
You know, when Sheldon gives you homework,
你可以拒绝
you don't have to do it.
其实你拒绝更好
In fact, it's better if you don't,
不然搞得我们几个很尴尬
otherwise it makes the rest of us look bad.
-各位好  -你好
- Hi, guys. - Hey. Hello.
拉杰  跟我说话
Yo, Raj, talk to me.
抱歉  耍你而已
I'm sorry, just screwing with you.
霍华德  你干嘛不打电话给伯纳黛特
Hey, Howard, why haven't you called Bernadette?
她说什么了吗
Did she say something?
她说你一个星期没跟她联系了
Yeah, she said she hasn't heard from you in a week.
我以为你喜欢她呢
I thought you liked her?
是喜欢  但她要我给个承诺
I do, but she wants a commitment
我又不确定她是不是我喜欢的类型
and I'm not sure she's my type.
她都愿意免费跟你约会
She agreed to go out with you for free.
你还想怎么样
What more do you need?
伯纳黛特是很好
Look, Bernadette is really nice.
我只是一直觉得  当我想认真的对待感情时
I just always thought when I finally settle down
对方应该是一个
into a relationship, it would be with someone,
你知道  一个特别的人
you know, different.
怎么特别
Different how?
更像《变形金刚》里的梅根·福克斯啦
Well, you know, more like Megan Fox from Transformers.
或者《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》里的
Or Katee Sackhoff
凯蒂·萨克霍夫啦
from Battlestar Galactica.
你嗑药啦
Are you high?
你跟《宇宙威龙》里有三个咪咪的
You'd have a better shot with the three-breasted
火星妓女在一起的可能性更大点
Martian hooker from Total Recall.
你说的太不实际了
Okay, now you're just being unrealistic.
那部电影都差不多20年了
Anyway, that movie was like 20 years ago.
想想那些咪咪该下垂成什么样了
Imagine how saggy those thing would be.
霍华德  你想守着你的荒诞幻想不放
Howard, you're going to throw away a great girl like Bernadette
而放过像伯纳黛特这么好的女生吗
because you're holding out for some ridiculous fantasy?
你的感情定下来了不代表我也要这样吧
Hey, just because you settled doesn't mean I have to.
喂  我在这坐着呢
Excuse me, I'm sitting here.
我又没有和莱纳德定下来
Hey, I did not settle for Leonard.
他显然不像我通常约会的类型
I mean, obviously, he isn't the kind of guy I usually go out with...
体格上不像
you know, physically.
再说一次  我在呢
Again, I'm right here.
我的意思是  我不会以封面断定书的好坏
My point is, I do not judge a book by its cover.
我更在意人的内心
I am interested in the person underneath.
我在这吧  你看得见我
I am here, right? You see me.
我也在意人的内心啊
Hey, I'm interested in what's inside people, too,
但是希望内心外面包装点像
but why is it wrong to want those insides wrapped up in,
哈莉·贝瑞（肤色黑）的巧克力不对吗
say, the delicious caramel that is Halle Berry?
对  你也是巧克力装
Yes, you're delicious caramel, too.
行  我告诉为什么不对
All right, you know what, I will tell you
抱歉  我能插下话吗
why it's wrong... Excuse me, may I interject?
干嘛
What?
从生物学角度上说
Biologically speaking,
霍华德想找最佳伴侣繁殖后代
Howard is perfectly justified in seeking out the optimum mate
完全合情合理
for the propagation of his genetic line.
-谢谢  谢尔顿  -不过
- Thank you, Sheldon. - Now, whether that
但这种繁殖如果站在人类进化的角度来看
propagation is in the interest of humanity is, of course,
又是完全不同的问题
an entirely different question.
我是艾拉·弗莱托
This is Ira Flatow and you're listening
您正在收听的是公共广播电台的周五科学
to NPR's Science Friday.
今晚跟我们电话连线的是
Joining us today by phone
在加州帕萨迪纳办公室里的
from his office in Pasadena, California
谢尔顿·库珀博士
is Dr. Sheldon Cooper.
这个肯定很好玩
Oh, this is going to be a riot.
欢迎参加我们的节目  库珀博士
Thanks for being with us today, Dr. Cooper.
我很荣幸  艾拉
My pleasure, Ira.
我们讨论一下磁单极子吧
Now, let's talk about magnetic monopoles.
你能给听众解释一下什么是磁单极子吗
Can you explain to our audience just what a monopole is?
当然可以
Of course.
首先  一块普通的磁铁
First, consider an ordinary magnet which has,
即使教育程度再低的听众
as even the most uneducated
都应该知道  有两个磁极
in your audience must know, two poles.
南极和北极
A north and south pole.
把磁铁切成两半  则变成较小的两块磁铁
If you cut that in half, you have two smaller magnets,
每块都有南北两极
each with its own north and south pole.
库珀博士  我们的连线
Uh, Dr. Cooper, I think there might be
可能出了点问题
something wrong with our connection.
不  我听得很清楚
No, I hear you fine.
正如我刚刚说的  普通磁铁有两个磁极
As I was saying, an ordinary magnet has two poles.
磁单极子的主要特征是
The primary characteristic of a monopole
它只有一个磁极  因此称为磁单极子
is that it has only one pole, hence, monopole.
弦理论  或者说M理论
A requirement for string theory,
的一个必要条件
or M-theory, if you will,
是存在磁单极子
is the existence of such monopoles.
我本人曾带领一个考察队
I, myself, led an expedition
前往北极圈探寻这种粒子
to the Arctic Circle in search of said particles.
克瑞普克  我看到喷嘴了  你死定了
Kripke, I found the nozzle! I'm going to kill you!
真高兴你今晚能和我共浴
So nice you could join me this evening.
你跟往常一样漂亮
You're looking lovely as always.
过奖  霍华德
Thanks, Howard.
一向乐意加入你的手淫幻想
Always nice to be part of your masturbatory fantasies.
别这样嘛  凯蒂
Come on, Katee.
何必说得这么低俗呢
Don't make it sound so cheap.
抱歉  在浴缸里自欺欺人
I'm sorry, fiddling with yourself in the bathtub
确实是出类拔萃的行为
is a real class act.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们可以开始了吗
So, shall we get started?
当然
Sure.
但我能先问你个问题吗
But can I ask you a question first?
你想扮演赛昂人和殖民者吗
Do you want to play Cylon and colonist?
不
No.
我很奇怪  你明明可以和真人约会
I want to know why you're playing make-believe with me
却在这里和我玩性幻想游戏
when you could be out with a real woman tonight.
你是指伯纳黛特吗
You mean, Bernadette?
不  我是指莱娅公主(星战人物  路克·天行者的双胞胎妹妹)
No, I mean Princess Leia.
我当然指的是伯纳黛特
Of course I mean Bernadette.
她是个很好的女孩儿  真的喜欢你
She's a wonderful girl and she really likes you.
我知道  但她不是你
I know, but she's not you.
我又不是真实的
I'm not me.
真正的我现正在比弗利山庄
The real me is in Beverly Hills
和某个英俊高大的有钱人约会呢
Going out with a tall, handsome, rich guy.
真的吗  很高大吗
Really? Tall?
-一米九三呢  -哇哦
- Six-four. - Ouch.
问题在于  你遇到了一个好女孩
The point is, you've got a wonderful girl in your life,
但却宁愿整晚在浴缸里对着虚拟影像
And you're ignoring her in order to spend your nights
和浴巾性幻想  也不去理她
in the bathtub with a mental image and a wash cloth.
霍华德
Howard!
你到底在里面干嘛
What are you doing in there?
我在洗澡
I'm taking a bath!
你可别做啥其他猥琐的事
I hope that's all you're doing!
那浴缸我也要用
We share that tub!
别提醒我
Don't remind me!
老天
Oh, man.
都是泡泡  没有我子孙的容身之地了
All soaped up and no place to go.
哥们儿  你还好吧
How ya doin', buddy?
我在国家电台上被当众羞辱
I was humiliated on national radio.
能好受才怪
How do you think I'm doing?
拜托  没这么夸张吧
Come on, it wasn't that bad.
你们来干嘛
What do you want?
(绿野仙踪中的麦琪肯人欢迎多萝西)
: We represent the Lollipop Guild,
我们是棒棒糖团队  欢迎你的到来
and we want you.
好啊  克瑞普克捉弄了你一下
Okay, so Kripke played a joke on you.
不好笑
It wasn't funny.
-我觉得很好笑  -拉杰
- I thought it was funny. - Raj.
你也笑了啊
You laughed.
你笑了吗
Did you laugh?
我笑得滚到地板上了
I fell on the floor.
好吧  这次是他赢了
All right, he got you.
你可以以牙还牙嘛
You can get him back.
我才不要堕落到他那种水准
I refuse to sink to his level.
你落不了  体内充满了氦气
You can't sink. With all that helium in you,
遇水不飘走就算你走运啦
you're lucky you don't float away.
你当真认栽了吗
Are you really admitting defeat?
我从不认栽
I never admit defeat.
很好
Good.
但是  从另一个方面讲
However, on an unrelated topic,
我再也抬不起头做人了
I am never getting out of this bed again.
那何不这样  你设法捉弄克瑞普克
What if you could make Kripke
让他看起来比你更蠢
look even sillier than he made you look?
我觉得这不可能  老兄
I don't think that's possible, dude.
你尽说些丧气话
You're not helping.
我本就不是来说好话  我是来吐糟的
I didn't come to help, I came to mock.
谢尔顿  你现在得好好想想
Sheldon, what you need to do is figure out a way
到底怎么报复克瑞普克
to exact vengeance on Kripke, like, uh,
好比蝙蝠侠把疯子罪犯小丑扔进了
like, how the Joker got back at Batman for putting him
亚克汗疯人院  事后他不是越狱了吗
in the Arkham Asylum for the Criminally Insane.
是啊  他不光是待在里面对其他
That's true. He didn't just stay there and talk about
精神病恶棍大吐苦水
His feelings with the other psychotic villains.
还越狱了  还对哥谭市的供水系统投毒
He, he broke out and poisoned Gotham's water supply.
好吧
Well...
-那我该给克瑞普克下毒  -不
- I suppose I could poison Kripke. - No!
不  这其实很简单
No. It's a simple matter.
有那么几种有毒化学物
There are several toxic chemicals
尸检是查不出来的
that'd be untraceable in an autopsy.
你抓到了要领
Okay, uh, that's the spirit,
但手段可以温柔点
but, um, let's dial it back
不要置人于死地
to a non-lethal form of vengeance.
这样  在他的办公室椅子上弄个放屁垫
How about we whoopee cushion on his office chair?
他一坐下  听起来就像是有胃气胀
He'll sit down, it'll sound like
尽管他不是真有胃气胀
he's flatulent, even though he's not.
还是再想想吧
Let's keep thinking.
老兄  你可来晚了
Oh, gee, you're too late.
斯嘉丽·乔纳森和神奇女侠
Scarlett Johansson and Wonder Woman were just in here
刚在这里轮番歌颂神经质和胆小鬼呢
trolling around for neurotic, little weasels.
我来找伯纳黛特  她今天上班吗
I came to talk to Bernadette. She's working today, right?
是啊  但我觉得她不想见你
Yes, but I don't think she wants to see you.
为啥
Why not?
得了  霍华德  你伤害了她
Come on, Howard. You hurt her feelings
一个星期都不给人家电话
by not calling her all week.
加上我还说了你不少坏话
Plus, I've kind of been talkin' some smack about ya.
好啊  霍华德
Hello, Howard.
等下  伯纳黛特  我有话对你说
Wait, Bernadette, I need to talk to you.
现在不成  我在工作呢
I can't now, I'm working.
就一会儿
This will only take a second.
你之前让我好好考虑
You asked me to think about where
我们之间的关系  好吧我想过了
our relationship was going, and I did.
伯纳黛特
Bernadette?
你愿意嫁给我吗
Will you marry me?
我不明白  这算是玩笑吗
Is this more comedy that I don't understand?
不  我是认真的
No. I'm serious.
你是我生命中的唯一
I'm never going to find another girl like you
重要的是  你是真心喜欢我
who likes me and is, you know, real.
这不是开玩笑吗
So, this isn't a joke?
-不是  -那你铁定疯了
- No. - Then you're insane.
我觉得自己这是突施奇招
I prefer to think of myself as quirky.
霍华德  我们只约会了三次
Howard, we've only been on three dates.
甚至还没上过床
We haven't even had sex yet.
你说得对
Fair enough.
你什么时候下班
When's your break?
好事将成  你们嫉妒我了不是
Don't you just hate when this happens?
好了  用这个来复仇如何
All right, how's this for revenge?
一剂过氧化氢[双氧水]
A solution of hydrogen peroxide,
加上一剂饱和碘化钾
and one of saturated potassium iodide.
这又是什么
What's this?
山露汽水[碳酸饮料]
Mountain Dew.
啊  真是提神醒脑
Ahh, refreshing.
然后将这两样化学制剂  与普通洗碗剂结合
We're going to combine these chemicals with ordinary dish soap,
就会放热  释放出氧
creating a little exothermic release of oxygen.
泡沫复仇记
Foamy vengeance.
完全正确
Yes, exactly.
谢尔顿  这招实在是高
This is brilliant, Sheldon.
但你怎么布置到克瑞普克的办公室
How are we going to deploy it in Kripke's office?
早就布置好了
Already taken care of.
注意看
Observe.
通过迷你摄像头拍摄到的克瑞普克实验室实况
This is a live shot of Kripke's lab via a mini webcam
拜我偷塞到看门人衬衫口袋里的美钞所赐
I was able to install, thanks to a dollar bill
我才能装了这个迷你摄像头
discreetly placed in the night janitor's shirt pocket.
与此同时
At the same time,
还将大量这样的化学制剂
I also secured large quantities of these chemicals
放到了他的天花板顶上
above the tiles in the drop ceiling.
哦  谢尔顿
Oh, Sheldon,
你让我想起年轻时的莱克斯·卢瑟[后成为超人的死敌]
you remind me of a young Lex Luthor.
您太过奖了  先生
You flatter me, sir.
-我猜猜  带运动感应器的  -是的
- Let me guess: motion sensors? - Yes.
一旦克瑞普克走到屋子中间
The reaction will be triggered
感应器就会触发
when Kripke reaches the center of the room.
木哈哈
Mwah, ha, ha.
我不得不承认  我很佩服你
I gotta say, I am really impressed.
这绝对是谢尔顿式的复仇方式
This is truly the Sheldon Cooper way to get even.
这招或许技术含量不高
It may be low-tech,
但我还是坚持认为  放屁坐垫自有其喜剧效应
but I still maintain the whoopee cushion has comic validity.
克瑞普克来了
Here comes Kripke!
跟他一起的是谁
Who is that with him?
我想那是我们大学的校长
I believe that's the president of the university.
还有理事会成员  快中止  中止
And the board of directors.Abort! Abort!
没有中止程序
There is no "abort."
你怎么能不设中止程序
How could you not put in an "abort?"
我疏忽了  好了吧
I made a boo-boo, all right?
塞伯特校长  相信理事会将很欣慰地看到
I think the board will really appreciate
我们将国安局的拨款运用得如此之好
how well we're using that NSA grant, President Seibert.
这里是我们的微电脑控制的等离子...
Right here we have a micro-controlled plasma...
看上去就像洗衣日那天的恒河
Wow. Looks like the Ganges on laundry day.
至少他们不知道是你干的
At least they don't know it was you.
你好  克瑞普克
Hello, Kripke.
你此刻遭遇的经典恶作剧
This classic prank comes to you
来自恶意复仇的谢尔顿·库珀
from the malevolent mind of Sheldon Cooper.
如果你想看看自己那张蠢蛋脸
If you'd like to see the look on your stupid face,
这段视频即刻就会上传到YouTube
this video is being instantly uploaded to YouTube.
并感谢莱纳德·霍夫斯塔德和拉杰·库萨帕里
Oh, and a hat tip to Leonard Hofstadter and Raj Koothrappali
感谢他们在复仇大业中对我的支持与鼓励
for their support and encouragement in this enterprise.
我计划逃回印度去  你呢
Well, I'm going back to India.What's your plan?
给  7号桌给的小费
Hey, here's your tip from table seven.
谢谢
Oh, thanks.
麦克风测试  再次测试
Testing. Check.Check two.
这回又怎么了
Oh, now what?
想让我扔他出去吗
You want me to throw him out?
不用  没事的
No, that's okay.
你确定  他个子那么小
Are you sure? He's small.
我打赌我肯定能给他来个漂亮的背摔
I bet I can get a nice, tight spiral on him.
这一曲  我想献给
I want to dedicate this number
一位被我伤害了的好姑娘
to a great gal who I've done wrong.
伯纳黛特[曲调来自The Four Tops乐队的《Bernadette》]
Bernadette
我感到非常抱歉
* I am so sorry for
因我向你求婚之事
* Trying to propose to you
伯纳黛特
* Bernadette
你觉得我行事疯狂
* You found it creepy
但那就是我的风格
* But that's just the kind of thing I do *
我知道现在说爱还太早
* I know now it was too soon to talk of love *
那只是我泡澡时突发的奇想
* It was just a crazy idea that came to me in my tub *
但伯纳黛特  请再给我一次机会
* But, Bernadette, give me one more chance *
亲爱的伯纳黛特
* Sweet Bernadette
我保证很快找到窍门
* I'll get the hang of this thing *
找到浪漫的窍门  亲爱的伯纳黛特
* They call romance, Sweet Bernadette *
我梦想着能够再一次
* I dream to once again
吻上你的双唇  亲爱的伯纳黛特
* Kiss your lips, Sweet Bernadette *
您的裙下之臣
* Sincerely yours
霍华德·沃罗威茨
* Howard Wolowitz
伯纳黛特
* Bernadette...
-实在听不下去了  -你开什么玩笑
- Oh, I am so sorry. - Are you kidding?
那是别人为我所做的  最浪漫的事
That's the most romantic thing anyone's ever done for me.
伯纳黛特  谢谢芝士蛋糕工厂
* Bernadette!  Thank you, Cheesecake Factory!